Guide to the Montana Power Company Predecessor Company records 1880-1947
Montana Historical Society
- Butte General Electric Company
  - Reports
    - Untitled reports on water flow of Big Hole River, 1893-1897 (Box-folder 17 / 4)
  - Miscellany
    - Damage from April 1899 fire (Box-folder 17 / 5)
- Butte Lighting and Power Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, 1899-1906 (Box-folder 17 / 6)
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, 1899-1901 (Box-folder 17 / 7)
  - Financial Records
    - General ledger, 1901 (Volume 50)
    - Journal, 1899-1901 (Volume 51)
  - Legal Documents
    - Agreement with Montana Power Transmission Company; applications for arc and incandescent lights, 1900-1901 (Box-folder 17 / 8)
  - Organizational Records
    - Certificate of incorporation; minutes, 1899, 1900 (Box-folder 17 / 9)
  - Miscellany
    - Index to original papers and certified copies; statistics on water flow in Big Hole River, 1900-1903 (Box-folder 17 / 10)
- Butte Missoula Realty Company
  - General Correspondence
    - J.W. Ward, company secretary, 1915 (Box-folder 17 / 11)
- Capital City Improvement Company
  - Financial Records
    - Financial statements, 1907-1910 (Box-folder 18 / 1-3)
    - General ledger, 1906-1911 (Volume 52)
    - General ledger: subsidiary accounts, 1909-1911 (Volume 53)
    - Journal, 1906-1911 (Volume 54)
    - Journal: subsidiary accounts, 1909-1911 (Volume 55)
    - Voucher registers, 1907-1911 (Volume 56-57)
  - Organizational Records
    - Articles of incorporation, 1906 (Box-folder 18 / 4)
- Capital City Power Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, undated (Box-folder 19 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Journal (includes detailed explanations of each item), 1907-1910 (Box-folder 19 / 2)
  - Legal Documents
    - Merger agreement with United Missouri River Power Company, 1910 (Box-folder 19 / 3)
    - Mortgage discharge, 1914 (Box-folder 19 / 4)
  - Organizational Records
    - Excerpts of minutes; stockholder lists, 1907-1914 (Box-folder 19 / 5)
    - Stockholder ledger [Oversize Box], 1907-1909 (Oversizebox 4)
    - Stockholder register and transfer book, 1907-1910 (Box-folder 19 / 6)
- Capital Lighting Company
  - Organizational Records
    - Stockholder transfer book, 1895-1896 (Box-folder 19 / 7)
- Chinook Municipal Lighting Plant
  - Reports
    - Public Service Commission audit report by J.H. Bonner, 1919 (Box-folder 19 / 8)
- Citizens Electric Light Company / Citizens Electric Company (Lewistown)
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, 1898 (Box-folder 19 / 9)
  - Financial Records
    - Trial balances; inventory, 1911, undated (Box-folder 19 / 10)
    - Voucher registers, 1910-1914 (Volume 58-59)
  - Legal Documents
    - Miscellaneous, 1902-1911 (Box-folder 19 / 11)
  - Organizational Records
    - Minutes, 1910-1915 (Box-folder 19 / 12)
    - Stock certificates, 1906-1911 (Box-folder 19 / 13)
    - Stockholder ledger, 1889-1892 (Box-folder 19 / 14)
    - Stockholder transfer journal, 1889-1892 (Box-folder 19 / 15)
- Clark-Missoula Power Company
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - State of Montana Advancement Association, 1914 (Box-folder 20 / 1)
  - Court Papers
    - C. LaForge vs. Clark-Missoula Power Company and Clark-Montana Realty Company, 1913 (Box-folder 20 / 2)
  - Employment Records
    - Payrolls and time checks, 1910-1916 (Box-folder 20 / 3-7)
  - Financial Records
    - Financial statements [Oversize Box], 1911-1916 (Oversizebox 4)
    - General ledgers, 1910-1916 (Volume 60-61)
    - Journal, 1910-1916 (Volume 62)
    - Trial balances, 1910-1913 (Box-folder 21 / 1)
    - Vouchers #1-31, 48-437, 1-58 [scattered], 1910-1913 (Box-folder 21 / 2-8)
    - Vouchers #59-501, 1914-1916 (Box-folder 22 / 1-4)
  - Legal Documents
    - Miscellaneous, 1910-1911 (Box-folder 22 / 5)
  - Miscellany
    - Specifications and request for bids, 1911 (Box-folder 22 / 6)
- Clark-Montana Realty Company
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress books: Clark Dam Project (Jerry Rourke, George Slack), 1905-1908 (Box-folder 23 / 1-2)
  - Court Papers
    - Clark-Montana Realty Company vs. Missoula County (re tax assessment), 1905-1908 (Box-folder 23 / 3)
  - Financial Records
    - Bank book: Clark Dam Project, 1909-1910 (Box-folder 23 / 4)
    - Cancelled checks: Clark Dam Project, 1909-1910 (Box-folder 23 / 5)
    - Cash book: Clark Dam Project, 1908-1910 (Box-folder 23 / 6)
    - Financial statements: Clark Dam Project, 1908 (Box-folder 24 / 1)
    - Journals: Clark Dam Project, 1903-1910 (Box-folder 24 / 2-3)
    - Ledger: Clark Dam Project, 1908-1910 (Box-folder 24 / 4)
    - Trial balances: Clark Dam Project, 1909-1910 (Box-folder 24 / 5)
    - Voucher register: Clark Dam Project, 1908-1910 (Volume 63)
  - Legal Documents
    - Affidavits re accidents on Clark Dam Project, 1909 (Box-folder 24 / 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1906-1911, 1928 (Box-folder 24 / 7)
  - Miscellany
    - Clark Dam Project field book, undated (Box-folder 24 / 8)
- Conrad Electric and Power Company
  - Financial Records
    - Collection book, 1910-1912 (Box-folder 25 / 1)
    - General ledgers, 1910-1918 (Box-folder 25 / 2-3)
    - Voucher register, 1910 (Box-folder 25 / 4)
    - Voucher register, 1911-1913 (Volume 64)
  - Organizational Records
    - Decree of dissolution of corporation, 1914 (Box-folder 25 / 5)
    - Minute book, 1911-1914 (Box-folder 25 / 6)
    - Stock certificates, 1911-1913 (Box-folder 25 / 7)
- Deer Lodge Electric Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, 1892-1942 (Box-folder 26 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Agents' cash books (collections), 1922-1924 (Volume 65)
    - Cash books, 1892-1903 (Box-folder 26 / 2-3)
    - Cash books, 1904-1922 (Volume 66-71)
    - General ledger, 1910-1912 (Box-folder 26 / 4)
    - General ledgers, 1913-1922 (Volume 72-74)
    - General ledgers, 1924-1928 (Box-folder 27 / 1-5)
    - General ledger, 1929 (Box-folder 28 / 1)
    - Journals, 1892-1909 (Box-folder 28 / 2-4)
    - Journals, 1910-1922 (Box-folder 29 / 1-4)
    - Report to Federal Trade Commission, 1928 (Box-folder 30 / 1)
    - Trial balances, 1892-1902 (Box-folder 30 / 2-3)
    - Trial balances, 1923-1928 (Oversizebox 4)
    - Voucher register [Oversize Box], 1922-1928 (Volume 75)
  - Organizational Records
    - Articles of incorporation, 1892 (Box-folder 30 / 4)
    - Record book (includes bylaws, minutes), 1892-1929 (Box-folder 30 / 5)
    - Stock certificates, 1892-1921 (Box-folder 31 / 1)
    - Stockholder lists, proxies, etc., 1921-1924 (Box-folder 31 / 2)
  - Miscellany
    - Job orders, 1923 (Box-folder 31 / 3)
- Dillon Electric Light and Power Company
  - Financial Records
    - General ledger, 1905-1908 (Box-folder 31 / 4)
    - Journal, 1905-1908 (Box-folder 31 / 5)
- Flathead Hydro-Electric Development
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence
    - Letters of General Land Office re withdrawal of lands for Flathead Project, 1910 (Box-folder 32 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Analysis of operations (construction expense accounts), 1930-1933 (Box-folder 32 / 2)
    - Analysis of operations (construction expense accounts), 1936-1938 (Box-folder 33 / 1)
    - Ledger, 1930-1933 (Box-folder 33 / 2)
- Gallatin Light, Power and Railway Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, 1892-1908 (Box-folder 34 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - General ledger, 1892-1893 (Box-folder 34 / 2)
    - General ledgers, 1893-1896 (Volume 76-77)
    - General ledger, 1898-1903 (Box-folder 34 / 3)
    - General ledgers, 1903-1906 (Box-folder 35 / 1-2)
    - General ledger, 1907-1909 (Volume 78)
    - Journal, 1892-1893 (Box-folder 35 / 3)
    - Journal, 1892-1909 (Box-folder 36 / 1)
    - Journal, 1893-1898 (Volume 79)
    - Journals, 1903-1905 (Box-folder 36 / 2-3)
    - Trial balances, 1893-1895 (Volume 80)
    - Trial balances, undated (Box-folder 36 / 4)
  - Organizational Records
    - Blank stock certificates, undated (Box-folder 36 / 5)
    - Stockholder ledger, 1892-1908 (Box-folder 36 / 6)
    - Stockholder transfer journal, 1892-1908 (Box-folder 36 / 7)
- Glacier Production Company
  - Employment Records
    - Payrolls [Oversize Box], 1939 (Oversizebox 5)
  - Financial Records
    - Financial statements, 1938-1941 (Volume 81-84)
    - Inventory, 1939 (Box-folder 37 / 1)
    - Invoices [arranged alphabetically within each month], 1939 (Box-folder 37 / 2-8)
    - Invoices [arranged alphabetically within each month], 1939 (Box-folder 38 / 1-5)
    - Progress billing; promissory note, 1939, 1940 (Box-folder 38 / 6)
  - Organizational Records
    - Articles of incorporation; bylaws; dissolution, 1936-1943 (Box-folder 39 / 1)
- Great Falls Electric Light And Power Company
  - Financial Records
    - Journals, 1890-1894 (Volume 85-86)
- Great Falls Electric Properties
  - Financial Records
    - Journal [continued from Boston and Great Falls Electric Light and Power Company], 1906-1908 (Volume 87)
    - Transfer ledger [continued from Boston and Great Falls Electric Light and Power Company], 1909-1912 (Box-folder 39 / 2)
    - Warehouse journals, 1907-1913 (Volume 88-89)
  - Organizational Records
    - Record book (includes certificate of incorporation; bylaws; minutes), 1906 (Box-folder 39 / 3)
    - Minutes, 1906-1909 (Box-folder 39 / 4)
- Great Falls Land Improvement Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous, 1918, 1927-1943 (Box-folder 40 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Audits, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 40 / 2)
    - Cash book, 1926-1943 (Volume 90)
    - Checkstubs, 1922-1935 (Box-folder 40 / 3)
    - General ledger, 1909-1943 (Box-folder 40 / 4)
    - Insurance, 1912-1918 (Box-folder 40 / 5)
    - Journal, 1927-1943 (Box-folder 40 / 6)
    - Land improvement book, 1912-1925 (Volume 91)
    - Recapitulation, etc., 1928-1935 (Box-folder 40 / 7)
    - Taxes: Cascade County and Great Falls, 1914-1922, 1935-1942 (Box-folder 40 / 8-9)
      RESTRICTED
    - Taxes: Cascade County notice of application for tax deed, 1936, 1939 (Box-folder 40 / 10)
    - Taxes: Cascade County notice to pay special taxes, 1918-1927 (Box-folder 40 / 11)
    - Taxes: Montana corporate, 1916-1944 (Box-folder 40 / 12)
    - Taxes: United States capital stock, 1917-1945 (Box-folder 40 / 13)
    - Taxes: United States corporate, 1915-1944 (Box-folder 41 / 1-2)
    - Trial balances, etc., 1926-1941 (Box-folder 41 / 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1908-1939 (Box-folder 41 / 4)
  - Legal Documents
    - Lot contracts: #243-485 [many gaps], 1910-1941 (Box-folder 41 / 5-8)
    - Miscellaneous (includes agreements, contracts, leases, mortgages, etc.), 1906-1940 (Box-folder 41 / 9)
  - Organizational Records
    - Annual reports of corporation, 1917, 1933-1941 (Box-folder 41 / 10)
- Great Falls Power Company
  - General Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (re navigability of Missouri River; Citizens Electric Company; bond issue; United Iron Works; Anaconda Copper Mining Company), 1908-1915 (Box-folder 42 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Analysis of interest and taxes during construction, 1915-1931 (Box-folder 42 / 2)
    - Big Falls Development [Rainbow]: construction orders #501-512, 1908-1909 (Box-folder 42 / 3)
    - Big Falls Development [Rainbow]: payroll [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], 1910-1912 (Oversize-folder 6)
    - Black Eagle Redevelopment: cash book, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 42 / 4)
    - Black Eagle Redevelopment: payroll register, 1926-1927 (Volume 92)
    - Cascade Branch: rate schedules, rules, etc., undated (Box-folder 42 / 5)
    - Collection register: Northern Division, 1917-1918 (Volume 93)
    - Great Falls Development [Volta/Ryan]: accounting, 1914-1916 (Box-folder 42 / 6)
    - Great Falls Development [Volta/Ryan]: boarding house and commissary daybook, 1915 (Box-folder 42 / 7)
    - Great Falls Development (Volta/Ryan): cash report, 1914-1915 (Volume 94)
    - Great Falls Development [Volta/Ryan]: cost estimate to complete and inventory, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 42 / 8)
    - Great Falls Development [Volta/Ryan]: cost sheets, 1913-1916 (Box-folder 42 / 9-12)
    - Great Falls Development [Volta/Ryan]: cost sheets for concrete in main dam, 1913-1915 (Box-folder 42 / 13)
    - Great Falls Development [Volta/Ryan]: daily distribution of time [originals too pale to film; Oversize Box], 1914 (Oversizebox 6)
    - Great Falls Development [Volta/Ryan]: labor distribution summary, 1913-1916 (Box-folder 43 / 1-4)
    - Great Falls Development [Volta/Ryan]: mass rock for Great Falls Dam, 1914 (Box-folder 43 / 5)
    - Great Falls Development [Volta/Ryan]: report on tests of concrete aggregates, 1914 (Box-folder 43 / 6)
    - Great Falls Development [Volta/Ryan]: trial balances, 1913-1916 (Box-folder 43 / 7-9)
    - Great Falls Development [Volta/Ryan]: trial balances (summaries), 1914-1916 (Box-folder 43 / 10)
    - Holter Development: cash book, 1916-1918 (Volume 95)
    - Invoices: A-S, 1913-1915 (Box-folder 43 / 11-13)
    - Invoices: Three Forks Portland Cement Company, 1913-1914 (Box-folder 44 / 1-2)
    - Invoices: U-W, 1913-1915 (Box-folder 44 / 3)
    - Job orders, 1922-1928 (Box-folder 44 / 4)
    - Morony Hydro Electric Development: cable and conduit lists and drawings, 1929 (Box-folder 44 / 5)
    - Operating reports, August1910- June 1912 (Box-folder 44 / 6-9)
    - Operating reports, July-December 1912 (Box-folder 45 / 1)
    - Power statements, 1922-1924 (Box-folder 45 / 2)
    - Rainbow Dam: construction orders, 1908-1910 (Box-folder 45 / 3-4)
    - Rainbow Dam: cost sheets, 1909-1910 (Box-folder 45 / 5)
    - Rainbow Dam: freight and invoice ledger, 1910 (Box-folder 45 / 6)
    - Rainbow Dam: freight and invoice record, 1908-1910 (Box-folder 46 / 1)
    - Rainbow Dam: journal entries (includes Big Falls Dam and transmission line), 1908-1911 (Box-folder 46 / 2)
    - Rainbow Dam: ledger, 1908-1909 (Box-folder 46 / 3)
    - Rainbow Dam: material record and engine report, 1908-1910 (Box-folder 46 / 4)
    - Rainbow Dam: payroll, 1910 (Box-folder 46 / 5)
    - Rainbow Dam: payroll [Oversize: see Archives Map Case], 1910-1912 (Oversize-folder 7)
    - Rainbow Extension: cash book, 1917 (Volume 96)
    - Rainbow Extension: delivery of equipment and supplies, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 47 / 1)
    - Rainbow Extension: labor distribution, 1916 (Box-folder 47 / 2)
    - Rainbow Extension: trial balances, 1916 (Box-folder 47 / 3)
    - Report to Federal Trade Commission, 1928 (Box-folder 47 / 4)
    - Tax data, 1912-1929 (Box-folder 47 / 5)
    - Trial balances, 1914-1915 (Volume 97)
    - Volta Station: labor distributions, payroll, misellany, 1915-1916 (Box-folder 47 / 6)
    - Voucher registers, 1910-1913, 1916-1923 (Volume 98-101)
    - Miscellaneous, 1910-1929 (Box-folder 47 / 7)
  - Legal Documents
    - Contract with S. Morgan Smith Company for turbines, 1926 (Box-folder 47 / 8)
    - Deed from Anaconda Copper Mining Company, 1927 (Box-folder 47 / 9)
    - Deed to Montana Power Company for Volta Plant, 1929 (Box-folder 47 / 10)
    - Mortgages, 1911-1929 (Box-folder 47 / 11)
    - Permits for transmission lines, 1911-1913 (Box-folder 48 / 1)
    - Power contracts: Anaconda Copper Mining Company, 1916-1932 (Box-folder 48 / 2)
    - Power contracts: B, 1911-1921 (Box-folder 48 / 3)
    - Power contracts: Chicago, Milwaukee and St. Paul Railway Company, 1912-1929 (Box-folder 48 / 4)
    - Power contracts: C-U, 1911-1922 (Box-folder 48 / 5-7)
    - Transfer of property from Great Falls Water Power and Townsite Company, 1910 (Box-folder 48 / 8)
  - Organizational Records
    - Certificate of incorporation; statement of dissolution; stockholder lists; miscellany, 1910-1931 (Box-folder 48 / 9)
    - Minutes excerpts and notes, 1910-1929 (Box-folder 48 / 10)
  - Reports
    - Annual reports, 1915, 1917 (Box-folder 48 / 11)
    - Excerpts from "Report of Missouri River Commission" listing benchmarks, 1891 (Box-folder 48 / 12)
    - Great Falls Development [Volta/Ryan]: report on electric heaters, 1915 (Box-folder 48 / 13)
    - History of company (includes drawings and photos of dams and power plants, histories of service in each town, etc.), 1938 (Box-folder 48 / 14)
    - "Inspection of the Rosebud Project" (satirical poem by Joe Bell and Frank Scotten), undated (Box-folder 49 / 1)
    - "Power development at Great Falls, Montana: a description of the Great Falls of the Missouri River, and the system of the Great Falls Power Company" by Max Hebgen, 1910 (Box-folder 49 / 2)
    - Reports by John Edgerton on cement, 1914-1915 (Box-folder 49 / 3)
  - Speeches
    - Lecture by John D. Ryan on property and bonds of company, 1912 (Box-folder 49 / 4)
  - Subject File
    - Chicago, Milwaukee and Saint Paul Railway Company electrification project, 1912-1916 (Box-folder 49 / 5)
  - Miscellany
    - Charts on power load, transmission lines, etc., 1910-1928 (Box-folder 49 / 6)
    - "Directions for erecting Remco continuous stove pipe", undated (Box-folder 49 / 7)
    - List of employees and salaries/wages, 1914 (Box-folder 49 / 8)
    - Specifications for Great Falls Development [Volta/Ryan], 1914-1915 (Box-folder 49 / 9)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 49 / 10)
- Great Falls Street Railway Company / Montana Power Company Street Railway System
  - General Correspondence
    - Other street railway companies (re policies on reduced prices, wage scales, employee discipline, unions, etc.), 1913-1915 (Box-folder 50 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Financial statement at time of abandonment, 1913-1927 (Box-folder 50 / 2)
    - General ledger, 1890-1893 (Box-folder 50 / 3)
    - General ledger, 1894-1904 (Volume 102)
    - Journal, 1894-1899 (Volume 103)
    - Journal, 1900-1906 (Box-folder 50 / 4)
  - Organizational Records
    - Miscellaneous (includes articles of incorporation, minutes, bylaws, stock certificates, abandonment), 1890-1936 (Box-folder 50 / 5)
  - Subject Files
    - Fare register systems, 1915-1917 (Box-folder 50 / 6)
    - Fare register systems: Ohmer Rapid Transit System, 1913-1916 (Box-folder 50 / 7)
    - Fenders, 1916 (Box-folder 51 / 1)
    - Rail construction, 1916 (Box-folder 51 / 2)
    - Rotary converters, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 51 / 3)
    - Special work, 1916 (Box-folder 51 / 4)
    - Street railway signals, 1916-1917 (Box-folder 51 / 5)
    - West side bus propositions: F-Y (includes advertising brochures from bus manufacturers and dealers), 1923-1924 (Box-folder 51 / 6-9)
  - Miscellany
    - Accident records, 1917-1922 (Box-folder 51 / 10)
    - Time table, 1915 (Box-folder 51 / 11)
- Great Falls Water Power and Townsite Company / Great Falls Townsite Company
  - Historical Material
    - General information and history, undated (Box-folder 52 / 1)
  - Interoffice Correspondence
    - Charles H. Benedict to Samuel Nichols, 1887-1889 (Box-folder 52 / 2)
    - C.A. Broadwater to Samuel Nichols, Charles M. Webster, and A.E. Dickerman, 1887-1890 (Box-folder 52 / 3-8)
    - W.C. Toomey; John J. Toomey (St. Paul); W.H. Perrott (Great Falls), 1902-1905 (Box-folder 52 / 9-13)
    - John J. Toomey (St. Paul); T.H. Larkin (Great Falls), 1906 (Box-folder 52 / 14)
    - John J. Toomey, J. Parker Veazey and J.H. Probst (Saint Paul); T.H. Larkin (Great Falls), 1907-1908 (Box-folder 53 / 1-3)
    - Construction Department, 1909-1910 (Box-folder 53 / 4)
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Wilmer Atkinson, 1888-1890 (Box-folder 53 / 5)
    - A-B, 1887-1890 (Box-folder 53 / 6-7)
    - Greenleaf Clark, 1887 (Box-folder 53 / 8)
    - J.C. Cowles, photographer, 1889 (Box-folder 53 / 9)
    - C-E, 1887-1890 (Box-folder 53 / 10-11)
    - Thomas H. Fairfax (Sioux Falls, S.D.), 1887-1889 (Box-folder 53 / 12)
    - F-L, 1887-1890 (Box-folder 53 / 13-14)
    - J. Kennedy Tod and Company, 1888-1890 (Box-folder 53 / 15)
    - Frank Langford (see also as secretary to C.A. Broadwater), 1888 (Box-folder 53 / 16)
    - Montana Central Railway Company, 1888-1889 (Box-folder 54 / 1)
    - Montana National Bank (correspondents include Ebenezer Sharpe, L.G. Phelps), 1888-1890 (Box-folder 54 / 2)
    - M-R, 1888-1890 (Box-folder 54 / 3-4)
    - Saint Paul, Minneapolis and Manitoba Railway Company (correspondents include Edward F. Nichols, C.H. Warren, F.S. Whitney, J. Bookwalter), 1887-1889 (Box-folder 54 / 5)
    - W.A. Stephens (Saint Paul, Minn.), 1887-1890 (Box-folder 54 / 6)
    - S-Z, 1887-1890 (Box-folder 54 / 7-9)
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress book, 1896-1898 (Box-folder 54 / 10)
  - General Correspondence
    - Anaconda Copper Mining Company (re purchases), 1908 (Box-folder 54 / 11)
    - Boston and Montana Consolidated Copper and Silver Mining Company, 1903, 1907 (Box-folder 54 / 12)
    - B-F, 1903-1908 (Box-folder 54 / 13)
    - J.M. Forbes and Company, 1904 (Box-folder 54 / 14)
    - Great Northern Railway Company (correspondents include J. Parker Veazey), 1903-1907 (Box-folder 54 / 15)
    - G-M, 1903-1908 (Box-folder 54 / 16)
    - National Surety Company (re employee bonding), 1903-1907 (Box-folder 54 / 17)
    - N-T, 1903-1907 (Box-folder 54 / 18)
    - B-W, 1921-1927, 1934 (Box-folder 54 / 19)
  - Employment Records
    - Assignments of wages; writs of attachment; garnishments: A-Y, miscellaneous, 1909-1910 (Box-folder 55 / 1-4)
    - Employment cards, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 55 / 5)
    - Payroll, 1910, 1940-1943 (Box-folder 55 / 6-7)
  - Financial Records
    - Balance sheets, 1903-1908, 1912 (Box-folder 55 / 8)
    - Cash books, 1887-1944 (Volume 104- 110)
    - Cash book: Townsite Company, 1910-1912 (Box-folder 55 / 9)
    - Cash books: Townsite Company, 1912-1943 (Volume 111- 116)
    - Cash receipts and disbursements, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 55 / 10)
    - Check register [Oversize Box], 1920-1944 (Oversizebox 7)
    - Checkstubs, 1910-1914 (Box-folder 55 / 11)
    - Construction order book, 1908-1909 (Volume 117)
    - Contract ledger, 1937 (Volume 118)
    - Financial and operating reports: Great Falls Townsite Company, 1930-1942 (Volume 119- 123)
    - Financial and operating reports: Great Falls Townsite Company, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 56 / 1-2)
    - Financial and operating reports: Great Falls Water Power and Townsite Company, 1929-1934 (Volume 124- 125)
    - Financial statements (weekly list of expenses; also includes some outgoing correspondence), 1889-1892 (Box-folder 56 / 3)
    - Financial statements: Rainbow Hotel, 1934-1935 (Box-folder 56 / 4)
    - General ledgers: Great Falls Water Power and Townsite Company, 1896-1910 (Volume 126- 127)
    - General ledger: Great Falls Water Power and Townsite Company, 1910-1912, 1930-1943 (Box-folder 56 / 5-7)
    - General ledger: Great Falls Townsite Company, 1912-1936 (Volume 128)
    - General ledger: Great Falls Townsite Company, 1936-1940 (Box-folder 57 / 1-5)
    - General ledger: Great Falls Townsite Company, 1941-1944 (Box-folder 58 / 1-4)
    - Great Northern Railway overcharges, 1909-1910 (Box-folder 59 / 1)
    - Inventories of Great Falls lots (see also subject file #16), 1903-1915 undated (Box-folder 59 / 2-4)
    - Inventories of Great Falls lots, lands and garden tracts, contracts, 1943 (Box-folder 59 / 5)
    - Inventories of office equipment, 1902-1908 (Box-folder 59 / 6)
    - Invoice book, 1890-1893 (Box-folder 59 / 7)
    - Invoices: Anaconda Copper Mining Company, 1910 (Box-folder 59 / 8-9)
    - Invoices: A-W, 1908 (Box-folder 60 / 1-2)
    - Job orders [2 only], 1922 (Box-folder 60 / 3)
    - Journal [Oversize Box], 1897 (Oversizebox 7)
    - Journal: Great Falls Townsite Company, 1910-1912 (Box-folder 60 / 4)
    - Journals: Great Falls Water Power and Townsite Company, 1896-1934 (Volume 129- 130)
    - Journals: Great Falls Townsite Company, 1912-1944 (Volume 131- 132)
    - Lot contract accounts (includes Rainbow Hotel rentals) [Oversize Box], 1943-1944 (Oversizebox 7)
    - Petty cash, 1938, 1942 (Box-folder 60 / 5)
    - Receipts [scattered], 1890 (Box-folder 60 / 6)
    - Rent ledgers, 1906-1921, 1940-1943 (Box-folder 60 / 7-9)